<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.5.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-08-24T00:24:52-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">The Settle Project</title><subtitle>An online résumé for Brett Settle, developed to showcase projects, work experience, and anything else worth documenting.  The Settle Project was created after I graduated from UCI in 2017.
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Welcome to the Albus Lepus</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/about/2017/08/23/Welcome-to-the-Albus-Lepus.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to the Albus Lepus" /><published>2017-08-23T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2017-08-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/about/2017/08/23/Welcome-to-the-Albus-Lepus</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/about/2017/08/23/Welcome-to-the-Albus-Lepus.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/arctic-hare.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;White Rabbit&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the first post of my new blog, the Albus Lepus! In latin, the phrase albus lepus translates to “white rabbit”, a nickname given to me for my near-albino appearance and quickness (on roller blades).  The first person to use the latin translation mistakenly called me “albus lupus”, which actually translates to “white wolf”.  It’s unnerving to switch from predator to prey so suddenly. I suppose there’s a lesson in there somewhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This blog acts as a sideproject/journal for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thesettleproject.com&quot;&gt;The Settle Project&lt;/a&gt;, and I hope to use it to better document my progress as a software developer.  I’ll be attempting to submit at least one post each week about programming projects, work stories, movie reviews, or anything that seems worth mentioning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So stay tuned for the first actual post! I’ve got plenty to talk about.  In the meantime, here are some tidbits about me:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Would voluntarily exchange feet for roller skate prosthetics&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When I’m not roller skating, I’m writing code&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Never lived outside of Southern California&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;My twin brother is in the Mathematics PhD program at Carnegie Mellon, PA, and my older sister teaches K-6 near Camp Pendleton, CA&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;My father named me after &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brett_Hull&quot;&gt;Brett Hull&lt;/a&gt;, the hockey player&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="about" /><category term="welcome" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry></feed>