<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.5.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://brettjsettle.github.io/thesettleproject/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://brettjsettle.github.io/thesettleproject/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-12-13T19:14:34+00:00</updated><id>http://brettjsettle.github.io/thesettleproject/</id><title type="html">The Settle Project</title><subtitle>An online résumé for Brett Settle, developed to showcase projects, work experience, and anything else worth documenting.
</subtitle><author><name>Brett Settle</name></author><entry><title type="html">Goon: Last of the Enforcers, hopefully</title><link href="http://brettjsettle.github.io/thesettleproject/movies/hockey/2017/09/08/Goon-Last-of-the-Enforcers.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Goon: Last of the Enforcers, hopefully" /><published>2017-09-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-09-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://brettjsettle.github.io/thesettleproject/movies/hockey/2017/09/08/Goon-Last-of-the-Enforcers</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://brettjsettle.github.io/thesettleproject/movies/hockey/2017/09/08/Goon-Last-of-the-Enforcers.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://mz-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/uploads/photo/file/304138/medium_ab34593e5d50ee9d40cacc0c171b4748-goon_last_of_the_enforcers_ver3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;
    Hooray! A review about a movie based on my favorite sport, hockey.  Goon: Last of the Enforcers is, at its core, modern day Slapshot: a real homage to the classic hockey comedy. It’s a tough task to emulate the satire that synonymized hockey and fighting, but the Goon films are giving it their best shot.  With plenty of blood, family values, and nonsense hockey, I think they fill the gap.
&lt;img src=&quot;http://25.media.tumblr.com/tumblr_leopnwmupU1qbo11ro1_500.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Hansen brothers&quot; /&gt;
    My Dad is correct that no one can replace Paul Newman’s sass, but the Goon movies switch it up by focusing on wannabe-Hansen-brother Doug Glatt, played by Seann William Scott, a bouncer turned hockey player with more toes than brain cells.  Seriously, you’d think he was the dullest skate on the ice, but almost every player in the movie is brain damaged.  We owe that glorious dialog to Jay Baruchel, who also has a minor role in the movie as the uncomfortably raunchy best friend — he’s played this character so many times in these witless comedies that it’s almost uncomfortable to go back and watch How To Train Your Dragon.  Goon falls right into that category with some simple, quotable moments.
&lt;img src=&quot;https://68.media.tumblr.com/18acbe6596a5201d2926430aa7835d9f/tumblr_o0qs2yuLjb1srkr3to1_500.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Gay Porn Hard&quot; /&gt;
    A little plot synopsis for those who skipped the first Goon (and who can blame you).  Our dumbass protagonist is a brick-wall bouncer with a sleezy best friend and overbearing parents (y’know, like high school).  Some guy sees him kicking ass and recruits him to play hockey, despite the fact that he’s never worn skates before.  Cue montage… yadda yadda yadda… imagine Happy Gilmore without Adam Sandler… the team starts to win somehow… girl crushes on abusive hockey player (so hot!)… aaaaaaand denouement!  The antagonist arrives in the form of X-Men Wolverines brother, Liev Schreiber!  An hour of thinking “When will they get to the real hockey?” and right when they do it goes back to being a Boxing movie.  In the end our hero prevails and gets the girl and we all go home. Clap clap. Good comedy. Moving on with our lives. Nope!
&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/Dgil6B2.gif&quot; alt=&quot;This is actually fucking happening&quot; /&gt;
    Goon 2 shows up out of nowhere because Jay Baruchel has a crapton of money and a disturbing sense of humor (and a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nhl.com/canadiens/news/hab-at-heart-jay-baruchel/c-726593&quot;&gt;love for hockey&lt;/a&gt;.  Couldn’t he just sit around and get high with Seth Rogen (and not make a movie about it. Looking at you, This is the End).  This time our protagonist meets a new pair of fists, bearded psychopath Anders Cain, played by Wyatt Russel (from 22 Jump Street, I guess??) and gets beaten to a pulp in the first game, retiring his right arm from the sport just in time to stay home with his pregnant wife.  And the bearded psycho becomes team captain (because that’s how captain works in the NHL).  With Doug working in an insurance company’s basement, the team starts losing.
    Then, in a Rocky-esque comeback, Doug asks old-rival Liev Schreiber to teach him how to left hook, and escapes the monotony of his safe job to punch some dudes on ice.  He tries to appease his wife by avoiding fights but that’s not how hockey works, is it? More punching, more splattering blood. That’s hockey!
    All in all, Goon 2 tries to skate by like a regular movie by hinting at some life lessons: Family comes first, never give up, teamwork makes the dream work, and most importantly, fighting won’t actually solve all your problems.  I’d say it does a fine job, but really it’s just an hour and a half of dumb characters and uncomfortable raunchy joke scenes. Which, to be honest, is all we really expected.
&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/PlrV4XG.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Goons&quot; /&gt;
For those of you that haven’t been in a hockey locker room, this is not actually a poor representation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;    Even after all the hits this movie takes, it does resemble a modern day Slapshot, with a lot less class and just as little hockey relevance.  And for that, I give it &lt;strong&gt;2.8/5 hockey sticks.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/thesettleproject/images/stickrating.png&quot; alt=&quot;2.8/5 hockey sticks&quot; /&gt;
Personally, I think Doug Glatt’s story has come to an end, and I hope he really is the last of the enforcers, but for those out there who want more Goon, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.slashfilm.com/jay-baruchel-discusses-potential-goon-sequels/&quot;&gt;you might get your wish&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Brett Settle</name></author><category term="movies" /><category term="goon" /><category term="hockey" /><category term="comedy" /><summary type="html">    Hooray! A review about a movie based on my favorite sport, hockey. Goon: Last of the Enforcers is, at its core, modern day Slapshot: a real homage to the classic hockey comedy. It’s a tough task to emulate the satire that synonymized hockey and fighting, but the Goon films are giving it their best shot. With plenty of blood, family values, and nonsense hockey, I think they fill the gap.     My Dad is correct that no one can replace Paul Newman’s sass, but the Goon movies switch it up by focusing on wannabe-Hansen-brother Doug Glatt, played by Seann William Scott, a bouncer turned hockey player with more toes than brain cells. Seriously, you’d think he was the dullest skate on the ice, but almost every player in the movie is brain damaged. We owe that glorious dialog to Jay Baruchel, who also has a minor role in the movie as the uncomfortably raunchy best friend — he’s played this character so many times in these witless comedies that it’s almost uncomfortable to go back and watch How To Train Your Dragon. Goon falls right into that category with some simple, quotable moments.     A little plot synopsis for those who skipped the first Goon (and who can blame you). Our dumbass protagonist is a brick-wall bouncer with a sleezy best friend and overbearing parents (y’know, like high school). Some guy sees him kicking ass and recruits him to play hockey, despite the fact that he’s never worn skates before. Cue montage… yadda yadda yadda… imagine Happy Gilmore without Adam Sandler… the team starts to win somehow… girl crushes on abusive hockey player (so hot!)… aaaaaaand denouement! The antagonist arrives in the form of X-Men Wolverines brother, Liev Schreiber! An hour of thinking “When will they get to the real hockey?” and right when they do it goes back to being a Boxing movie. In the end our hero prevails and gets the girl and we all go home. Clap clap. Good comedy. Moving on with our lives. Nope!     Goon 2 shows up out of nowhere because Jay Baruchel has a crapton of money and a disturbing sense of humor (and a love for hockey. Couldn’t he just sit around and get high with Seth Rogen (and not make a movie about it. Looking at you, This is the End). This time our protagonist meets a new pair of fists, bearded psychopath Anders Cain, played by Wyatt Russel (from 22 Jump Street, I guess??) and gets beaten to a pulp in the first game, retiring his right arm from the sport just in time to stay home with his pregnant wife. And the bearded psycho becomes team captain (because that’s how captain works in the NHL). With Doug working in an insurance company’s basement, the team starts losing.     Then, in a Rocky-esque comeback, Doug asks old-rival Liev Schreiber to teach him how to left hook, and escapes the monotony of his safe job to punch some dudes on ice. He tries to appease his wife by avoiding fights but that’s not how hockey works, is it? More punching, more splattering blood. That’s hockey!     All in all, Goon 2 tries to skate by like a regular movie by hinting at some life lessons: Family comes first, never give up, teamwork makes the dream work, and most importantly, fighting won’t actually solve all your problems. I’d say it does a fine job, but really it’s just an hour and a half of dumb characters and uncomfortable raunchy joke scenes. Which, to be honest, is all we really expected. For those of you that haven’t been in a hockey locker room, this is not actually a poor representation.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Redwall: Separating Frontend from Backend</title><link href="http://brettjsettle.github.io/thesettleproject/code/python/2017/08/25/redwall.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Redwall: Separating Frontend from Backend" /><published>2017-08-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-08-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://brettjsettle.github.io/thesettleproject/code/python/2017/08/25/redwall</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://brettjsettle.github.io/thesettleproject/code/python/2017/08/25/redwall.html">&lt;p&gt;    I’ve spent countless hours sifting through &lt;a href=&quot;http://reddit.com/r/wallpaperdump&quot;&gt;/r/wallpaperdump&lt;/a&gt; for just the right wallpapers, downloading one in a thousand to my Wallpapers directory, and setting the desktop background to rotate through that directory.  When my roommates started pointing out how often I was browsing wallpapers, I decided to make a project out of it: &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/brettjsettle/redwall&quot;&gt;Redwall&lt;/a&gt;.  While plenty of web scrapers already exist, my goal was to simplify the transition from internet file to desktop background.  As with any project, there were plenty of lessons along the way:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;open-source&quot;&gt;Open Source&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;    A simple search led me to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/HoverHell/RedditImageGrab/tree/master/redditdownload&quot;&gt;RedditImageGrabber&lt;/a&gt; as an API to fetch post and image urls. Merged with the wallpaper setting function from &lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/1977694/how-can-i-change-my-desktop-background-with-python&quot;&gt;this StackOverflow post&lt;/a&gt; to update your wallpaper in real time,  most of the work was done for me. All I had to do was wrap these two files into one module and BOOM! Easy. All that remained was designing the interface. Better look at some examples…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;everything-exists-already&quot;&gt;Everything Exists Already&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;    Most image scrapers provide some basic filter options and show results asa giant mesh. If you click on an image it zooms in. All that jazz. But I just wanted a fullscreen image stepper that I could control with arrow keys, which somehow didn’t seem to exist. Until I stumbled on &lt;a href=&quot;http://imagoid.com&quot;&gt;imagoid&lt;/a&gt;.  A reddit image scraper for more than just wallpapers that offers fullscreen iteration with arrow keys, and it’s a webapp. (It’s seriously cool, check it out) Although I was discouraged, this project really interested me and I wanted to add my own twist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;straight-to-ui-aka-where-i-went-wrong&quot;&gt;Straight to UI (aka where I went wrong)&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;    My day job made heavy use of &lt;a href=&quot;https://riverbankcomputing.com/software/pyqt/intro&quot;&gt;PyQt&lt;/a&gt; to build windowed image analysis applications for researchers in the lab, and I loved the SDK so much I was using it everywhere. Even places it didn’t belong.  So I started designing the layout in PyQt while working on the merging the backend code.  Which reinforced the age old lesson:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Never design your API around your user interface.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately I was motivated enough to get a pretty neat result, so it all seemed worth it. I had all the functionality of a basic scraper, with background caching of images for nearly seamless scrolling.
&lt;img src=&quot;/thesettleproject/images/redwall_windowed_snap.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;Initial Result&quot; /&gt;
But I was having a lot of issues with the image scraping thread fighting the GUI thread for CPU.  I needed a simpler interface. Which also meant going back and cleaning up the API.  If you are interest in the windowed version, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/BrettJSettle/RedWall/tree/windowed&quot;&gt;the repo branch&lt;/a&gt; is still available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;simple-and-reliable&quot;&gt;Simple and reliable&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;    I stripped away all requirements other than BeautifulSoup, turned the image scraping into a Python iterator class, and wrote two wrappers for ease of use. Both are available via pip entry_points:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;language-bash highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# Images are shown on the desktop for 8 seconds (or whatever time specified by -i)&lt;/span&gt;
redwall_screensaver

&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;# A command line interface to iterate through images manually, with a help menu.&lt;/span&gt;
redwall_control

usage: redwall_control &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;-h] &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;--subreddit SUBREDDIT] &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;--previd previd]
                       &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;--score score] &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;--nsfwo] &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;--nsfw] &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;--title title]
                       &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;-i INTERVAL] &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;-v]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I can run &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;python_screensaver -i 20 --subreddit wallpaperdump&lt;/code&gt; and watch reddit wallpapers scroll by at an even pace while I’m at work.  Needless to say, after this project I was MUCH less interested in browsing wallpapers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more documentation and use cases of redwall, check out &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/brettjsettle/redwall&quot;&gt;the Github&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Brett Settle</name></author><category term="redwall" /><category term="python" /><category term="reddit" /><category term="wallpaper" /><category term="wallpapers" /><summary type="html">    I’ve spent countless hours sifting through /r/wallpaperdump for just the right wallpapers, downloading one in a thousand to my Wallpapers directory, and setting the desktop background to rotate through that directory. When my roommates started pointing out how often I was browsing wallpapers, I decided to make a project out of it: Redwall. While plenty of web scrapers already exist, my goal was to simplify the transition from internet file to desktop background. As with any project, there were plenty of lessons along the way:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to The Settle Project!</title><link href="http://brettjsettle.github.io/thesettleproject/welcome/2017/08/23/Welcome.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to The Settle Project!" /><published>2017-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://brettjsettle.github.io/thesettleproject/welcome/2017/08/23/Welcome</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://brettjsettle.github.io/thesettleproject/welcome/2017/08/23/Welcome.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/thesettleproject/images/arctic-hare.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;White Rabbit&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;    This is the first post of my blog! Hopefully I can make the most of these paragraphs to document my progress as a software developer, and as an individual. I’ll be attempting to submit at least one post each month about programming projects, work stories, movie reviews, or anything that seems worth mentioning.  If you have ideas for projects, or movies you think I should review, &lt;a href=&quot;/thesettleproject/contact&quot;&gt;send them to me&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;    I am choosing the arctic hare as my blog mascot in honor of my favorite spirit animal and nickname, &lt;em&gt;Albus Lepus&lt;/em&gt;. In latin, the phrase &lt;em&gt;albus lepus&lt;/em&gt; translates to “white rabbit”, an alias I earned for my near-albino appearance and quickness (on roller blades).  The first person to use the latin translation mistakenly called me &lt;em&gt;albus lupus&lt;/em&gt;, which actually translates to “white wolf”.  Only now realizing the mistake, it’s a bit unnerving to switch from predator to prey. I suppose there’s a lesson in there somewhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is just an informational post, but there are plenty of interesting posts to come. For now, here are some tidbits about me:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I would voluntarily exchange my feet for prosthetic roller skates&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When I’m not roller skating, I’m writing code&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’ve never lived outside of Southern California&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;My twin brother is in the Mathematics PhD program at Carnegie Mellon, PA, and my older sister teaches K-6 near Camp Pendleton, CA&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I was named me after &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brett_Hull&quot;&gt;Brett Hull&lt;/a&gt;, the hockey player&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I like to watch movies while I work. See &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/user/ur77436581/ratings?opfrule=httpDefault&quot;&gt;my list&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information about me, check out the &lt;a href=&quot;/thesettleproject/about/&quot;&gt;About&lt;/a&gt; page. Or just &lt;a href=&quot;/contact/&quot;&gt;email me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Brett Settle</name></author><category term="welcome" /><category term="welcome" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry></feed>